Hi, next these are dividing functions. We will look at dividing function already
안녕하세요, 다음은 나누기 함수입니다. 나누기 함수에 대해 살펴보겠습니다.
I have few videos on the decreasing functions
감소 함수에 대한 몇 가지 비디오가 있습니다.
Now this is called as dividing function reason if you see in the algorithm or a function
이것은 나누기 함수라고 불립니다. 알고리즘이나 함수에서
It is calling itself for n by 2 if n is passed then it is
n을 전달받으면 n을 2로 나누어 호출하기 때문입니다.
Dividing n see if our algorithm is taking any parameter. Let us say n
알고리즘이 어떤 매개변수를 받는다면, 예를 들어 n이라면
then it can reduce the value of n by either n minus 1 that is subtracting
n의 값을 n-1로 줄일 수 있습니다. 즉, 빼기
or decreasing or n by 2 that is a dividing or
또는 감소시키거나 n을 2로 나누는 것입니다. 즉, 나누기 또는
root n that is root function
루트 n, 즉 루트 함수입니다.
Right so for all these we can have different type of functions where the algorithm or a recursive function is calling itself again
이 모든 경우에 대해 알고리즘이나 재귀 함수가 다시 호출되는 다양한 유형의 함수가 있을 수 있습니다.
by root value of n or
n의 루트 값이나
Divided value of n or decreased value of n so already we have decreased value of n functions now
나누어진 n의 값 또는 감소된 n의 값으로 이미 감소된 n의 값 함수가 있습니다.
This is dividing value of the function if you have not seen those videos
이것은 함수의 나누기 값입니다. 그 비디오를 보지 않았다면
You can watch them now. Let us solve this one
지금 볼 수 있습니다. 이제 이것을 해결해 봅시다.
Let us prepare a recurrence relation. We will say this algorithm takes a t n time and
재귀 관계를 준비해 봅시다. 이 알고리즘이 t n 시간을 소요한다고 말할 것입니다.
There are two statements inside this one so this takes one unit of time and when this is a t n
이 안에 두 개의 문장이 있으므로 하나의 단위 시간이 걸리고, 이것이 t n일 때
What is this t n by 2?
t n을 2로 나눈 것은 무엇입니까?
Then what is the equation t n is equals to these two so this is t n by 2?
그러면 방정식은 t n은 이 두 개와 같으므로 t n을 2로 나눈 것입니다.
plus 1
더하기 1
That's the recurrence relation now. Let us write that recurrence relation here t n is equals to
이것이 재귀 관계입니다. 이제 그 재귀 관계를 여기 t n은
t n by 2
t n을 2로 나눈 것
plus 1
더하기 1
when n is
n일 때
See if you observe here. I have written 1 I
여기서 1을 썼다는 것을 보세요.
Have written 1 so if n is greater than 1 this is happening
1을 썼습니다. 그래서 n이 1보다 크면 이것이 발생합니다.
If n is equal to 1 then nothing so I can take constant or
n이 1과 같으면 아무것도 없습니다. 그래서 상수를 취하거나
write 1
1을 씁니다.
constant
상수
This is the recurrence relation now. Let us solve this one by using tree method
이것이 재귀 관계입니다. 이제 트리 방법을 사용하여 이것을 해결해 봅시다.
recursion tree method
재귀 트리 방법
t n is called
t n이 호출됩니다.
What are the steps 1 and t n by 2 so this is 1 and this is t n by 2?
단계 1과 t n을 2로 나눈 것은 무엇인가요? 그래서 이것이 1이고 이것이 t n을 2로 나눈 것입니다.
How much time t n takes 1 plus whatever the time taken by this we don't know the time for this one
t n이 걸리는 시간은 얼마인가요? 1 플러스 이 시간에 걸리는 시간, 우리는 이 시간에 대해 모릅니다.
So what is this this is 1 plus t n by 2 squared so that is n by 2 by 2 again
그래서 이것은 무엇인가요? 이것은 1 플러스 t n을 2로 나눈 것을 제곱한 것입니다. 그래서 다시 n을 2로 나눈 것입니다.
So this one is 1 t n by 2 cubed
그래서 이것은 1 t n을 2로 나눈 것을 세제곱한 것입니다.
How long we will continue we say that we'll continue for k times so if we continue for k times then this will be
얼마나 오래 계속할까요? 우리는 k번 계속할 것이라고 말합니다. 그래서 k번 계속하면 이것은
t of n by 2 power k
t n을 2의 k제곱으로 나눈 것이 됩니다.
See when this is getting divided and divided and divided at last what we will get
이것이 계속 나누어질 때 마지막에 무엇을 얻게 될까요?
The unity value or the unit value for division and multiplication is 1
나누기와 곱셈의 단위 값은 1입니다.
so it should stop at 1 and
그래서 1에서 멈춰야 합니다.
We know when n is equals to 1 answer is 1
우리는 n이 1일 때 답이 1이라는 것을 알고 있습니다.
So the purpose of go on dividing is to reach that 1
그래서 계속 나누는 목적은 1에 도달하는 것입니다.
So we assume that we have reached till n by 2 power k that is equal to 1
그래서 우리는 n을 2의 k제곱으로 나눈 것이 1에 도달했다고 가정합니다.
So now let us see what is the time
이제 시간을 봅시다.
See in this it is one step then one step in each there is only one step one step
여기서 한 단계, 그 다음 한 단계, 각각 한 단계씩 있습니다.
How many times this will take one one step total how many steps are there so we are doing it for k times
이것이 몇 번 걸릴까요? 한 단계씩, 총 몇 단계가 있나요? 우리는 k번 하고 있습니다.
So these are k steps
그래서 이것들은 k단계입니다.
So
그래서
It means time is k so it depends on the number of steps or the number of levels that this tree is having
시간은 k입니다. 이는 이 트리가 가지고 있는 단계 수나 레벨 수에 따라 다릅니다.
So that is equal to k see this one time then two time then three time up to k times
그래서 이것은 k와 같습니다. 한 번, 두 번, 세 번, k번까지입니다.
Right and we know that n by 2 power k is equals to 1
그리고 우리는 n을 2의 k제곱으로 나눈 것이 1이라는 것을 알고 있습니다.
Since n by 2 power k is equals to 1
n을 2의 k제곱으로 나눈 것이 1이기 때문에
Then this is n is equals to 2 power k then what is k?
n은 2의 k제곱과 같습니다. 그러면 k는 무엇인가요?
k is equals to log n base 2
k는 log n의 밑이 2입니다.
You send this power base to this side. So it becomes log n base 2
이 지수를 이쪽으로 보내면 log n의 밑이 2가 됩니다.
See, I'll write here if 2 power 5 is
여기 쓸게요. 만약 2의 5제곱이
Then 5 is equals to log 32 base 2
그러면 5는 log 32의 밑이 2입니다.
Log 32 base 2
log 32의 밑이 2입니다.
Right, so it means if you have a power b is equals to c then b is equals to log
즉, a의 b제곱이 c라면 b는 log
c base a
c의 밑이 a입니다.
So same way 2 power k is equals to n
그래서 같은 방식으로 2의 k승은 n과 같습니다.
2 power k is equals to n then k is equals to log n base 2 log n base 2
2의 k승이 n과 같다면, k는 log n의 밑이 2인 로그입니다.
So that's it. How many steps it is taking k steps. So what is the time taken?
그래서 끝입니다. 몇 단계가 걸리나요? k 단계입니다. 그러면 걸린 시간은?
Log n k k is log n so the answer for this is
로그 n, k는 로그 n이므로, 이것의 답은
Order of log n or say big O of log n
로그 n의 차수(Order) 또는 빅 오(Big O) 로그 n입니다.
So that's it this is using tree method now, let us solve the same thing using substitution method
그래서 끝입니다. 이것은 트리 방법(Tree method)을 사용한 것입니다. 이제 대입 방법(Substitution method)을 사용하여 같은 것을 풀어봅시다.
Let us solve this by substitution
대입법으로 이것을 풀어봅시다.
T n is equals to
T n은
T n by 2
T n 나누기 2
Plus 1 this is the first equation
더하기 1입니다. 이것이 첫 번째 방정식입니다.
Then what is T n by 2? See since T n is equals to T n by 2 plus 1
그러면 T n 나누기 2는 무엇일까요? T n은 T n 나누기 2 더하기 1이므로
Then T n by 2 will be what T n by 2 by 2 so n by 2 square plus 1
그러면 T n 나누기 2는 무엇일까요? T n 나누기 2 나누기 2, 그래서 n 나누기 2의 제곱 더하기 1입니다.
So we can substitute this one here
그래서 이것을 여기서 대입할 수 있습니다.
So this becomes what T n is equals to T n by 2 square plus 1
그래서 이것은 T n은 T n 나누기 2의 제곱 더하기 1이 됩니다.
This one then plus 1 as it is
이것에 더하기 1을 그대로 더합니다.
T n is equals to T n by 2 square plus 1 plus 1 2
T n은 T n 나누기 2의 제곱 더하기 1 더하기 1, 2입니다.
I'm adding them because these are just constant values 1 1 so I'm adding them
이것들은 단지 상수 값 1, 1이기 때문에 더하고 있습니다.
So it means in the next step what I get
그래서 다음 단계에서 얻는 것은 무엇인가요?
This is second one. So it means in next step what I get T n is equals to
이것이 두 번째입니다. 그래서 다음 단계에서 얻는 것은 T n은
T n by 2 cube
T n 나누기 2의 세제곱
plus 3
더하기 3입니다.
If we continue doing this then what I get
이렇게 계속하면 무엇을 얻을까요?
T n is equals to T n by 2 power k
T n은 T n 나누기 2의 k승
plus k
더하기 k입니다.
Fourth equation
네 번째 방정식입니다.
T n is equals to T n by 2 power k plus k
T n은 T n 나누기 2의 k승 더하기 k입니다.
Now we assume that n by 2 power k has became 1 that is n is equals to 1 so we assume this one
이제 n 나누기 2의 k승이 1이 되었다고 가정합니다. 즉, n은 1과 같습니다. 그래서 이것을 가정합니다.
n by 2 power k is equals to 1 because we are reducing it and reducing it up to 1
n 나누기 2의 k승은 1과 같습니다. 왜냐하면 우리는 그것을 1까지 줄이고 줄이고 있기 때문입니다.
So this has become 1 so therefore n is equals to 2 power k and
그래서 이것은 1이 되었습니다. 따라서 n은 2의 k승과 같습니다.
k is equals to log n
k는 log n과 같습니다
Now take that one T n is equals to T
이제 T n은 T와 같습니다
1 plus what is k log n
1 더하기 k는 log n입니다
T n is equals to what is the T 1 T 1 is 1
T n은 T 1과 같습니다. T 1은 1입니다
1 plus log n
1 더하기 log n
That's it. This is theta or big O of n
그게 다입니다. 이것은 세타(Theta) 또는 빅 오(Big O) n입니다
So we got the same answer
그래서 같은 답을 얻었습니다
So that's it this form of equation recurrence relation
그래서 이 형태의 방정식 재귀 관계입니다
We are getting the answer as log n
우리는 log n이라는 답을 얻고 있습니다
So we have solved using tree method as well as substitute substitution or induction method
그래서 트리 방법과 대입 또는 귀납 방법을 사용하여 해결했습니다
And we also have a master theorem for this one. So we will see few recurrence relations
그리고 이것을 위한 마스터 정리(Master Theorem)도 있습니다. 그래서 몇 가지 재귀 관계를 볼 것입니다
So then we will see Masters theorem for this one
그런 다음 이것을 위한 마스터 정리를 볼 것입니다